Indiana University I Association records C732
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University I Association records
1994-2010
Indiana University Archives
C732
1.8 cubic feet (3 boxes)
The I Association (formerly I-Men Association (1913-2006) and I-Women Association (1982-2006)) honors exceptional athletes at Indiana University Bloomington. This collection contains files about I Association alumni events and event planning, Board of Directors meeting information, I Association membership, and email, letter, and memo correspondence between I Association staff and alumni.
Biographical / Historical
The I-Men's Association was created in 1913 to honor male student athletes who earned varsity letters while competing for Indiana University. In 1982, an I-Women's Association was founded and in 2007, these two groups merged to create the I Association. Being an alumni organization, the I Association was a group within the IU Alumni Association until 2020, when it became part of the Department of Athletics. The I Association has held a variety of annual events for its members including I Association 25- and 50-year reunions, the Clevenger Award for individuals who have contributed outstanding services to the athletic program, golf outings, homecoming and tailgating festivities, and athletic activities for alumni living in Chicago and Indianapolis.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder heading.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, Board of Directors meeting notes and minutes, executive council booklets, I Association membership, and event flyers and planning information from 1994-2010 (bulk 1996-2009). Frequent correspondents include Karl Zacker (IUAA staff member and Executive Director of the I Association (2006-2013) and Tom Bolyard (I-Men's Association Board Member, Executive Secretary (1998-2004) and Executive Director (2005-2006)).
Separated Materials
2 Lifetime I-Men membership cards and a stack of 2006 football tickets were discarded.
Custodial History
This collection was transferred from the IU Alumni Association - I Association to the University Archives, March 2014.
Appraisal
Duplicate mailings and flyers pulled and discarded. Printouts from alumni profile database and forms with sensitive information were pulled and destroyed.
- 25 Year I-Men Reunion, 2000 (Box 1)
- 25 Year I-Men / I-Women Reunion (Box 1)
  - 2001 (Box 1)
  - 2002 (Box 1)
  - 2003 (Box 1)
  - 2004 (Box 1)
  - 2005 (Box 1)
  - 2006 (Box 1)
  - September 22, 2007 (Box 1)
- 50 Year I-Men Reunion (Box 1)
  - 1998 (Box 1)
  - 1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001 (Box 1)
  - 2006 (Box 1)
- 50 Year Reunion (1957-58), October 19-20, 2007 (Box 1)
- 50 Year Scripts, 2007 (Box 1)
- Alumni Association Event Planning, 1998-2009 (Box 1)
- Alumni Association Revenue & Expense, 1998-1999, 2003-2006 (Box 1)
- Alumni Trustee Election, 2001 (Box 1)
- Annual Award Winners (I-Men Association), circa 2000-2003 (Box 1)
- Board of Directors (I-Men Association), 1998-2007 (Box 1)
- Board of Directors Meetings (I-Men Association) (Box 1)
  - November 1996, May 1998-December 1999 (Box 1)
  - October 2003-February 2006 (Box 1)
  - May 18, 2007 (Box 1)
  - August 31st, 2007 (Box 1)
  - August 31st, 2007 (Box 1)
  - May 16, 2008 (Box 1)
  - January 24, 2010 (Box 1)
- Clevenger Award (Box 1)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2009 (Box 1)
- Clevenger Scripts, 2008 (Box 1)
- Cream & Crimson, 2007 (Box 1)
- Dicken's Boys, 2009 (Box 1)
- Dicken's Football Reunion, September 13-15, 2007 (Box 1)
- Emails / Memos (Box 1)
  - May 1994, January 1998-May 2002 (Box 1)
  - January 2004-October 2007 (Box 1)
- Events (I-Men), 1986, 1997-2006 (Box 1)
- Events (I-Women), 1998-2006 (Box 1)
- Events (Other), 1999-2007 (Box 1)
- Executive Council (Box 1)
  - June 18-19, 1999 (Box 1)
  - December 3-4, 1999 (Box 1)
  - June 16-18, 2000 (Box 1)
  - June 15-16, 2001 (Box 1)
  - December 7-8, 2001 (Box 1)
  - December 13-14, 2002 (Box 1)
  - December 3-4, 2004 (Box 1)
  - December 8-9, 2006 (Box 1)
- Founders Day 2009, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
- Golf Outing (Box 2)
  - 2003 (Box 2)
  - May 17, 2003 (Box 2)
  - May 21, 2005 (Box 2)
  - May 20, 2006 (Box 2)
  - May 19, 2007 (Box 2)
- Grotke Award Pamphlets, 2009-2010 (Box 2)
- Hall of Fame (Box 2)
  - 1998-2006 (Box 2)
  - 2008 (Box 2)
- Honors Convocation / Founder's Day, 2009 (Box 2)
- Honors Convocation (Box 2)
  - 2009-2010 (Box 2)
  - 2010 (Box 2)
- I Association, 2009 (Box 2)
- I Association Women's Award, 1997, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
- I-Men (general), 1997-2007 (Box 2)
- I-Women (general), 1997-2006 (Box 2)
- I-Women Special Request, 2007-2008 (Box 3)
- Mailers (I-Men), 1998-2007 (Box 3)
- Membership Committee (Phil Westfall), 2007-2008 (Box 3)
- Membership (I-Men), 1998-2006 (Box 3)
- Membership (I-Women), 1998-2004 (Box 3)
- Merchandise (I-Men), 1998 and undated (Box 3)
- Merger (I-Men / I-Women), 2006 (Box 3)
- Newspaper Clippings, 2004 (Box 3)
- Pamphlets, Maps, & Envelopes, 1999-2009 (Box 3)
- Peach Bowl Reunion, 2007 (Box 3)
- Website, 2008-2009 (Box 3)
- Wrestling, October 5-6, 2007 (Box 3)